A Guide to the Letters of North Carolina families, 1813-1914 (bulk 1813-1896)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: North Carolina Counties General, 1813-1849
  - C. Dewey, Bank of the State of North Carolina, to James G. Stanley, Newbern, North Carolina: clearance of debt. 1836 Jun 16
  - John and Mary Walker, Fairfield District, South Carolina, to Andrew McCants, Talbot County, Union Post Office, Georgia: crops, cotton and corn prices. 1836 Dec 1
  - George D. Phillips, Clarksville, Georgia, to Maj. Thomas B. Cooper, Jefferson, Cherokee County, Alabama: attempt on the life of the overseer by "one of his negro fellows" named "George," history of the life and recent activities of "George," request for knowledge of "George's" whereabouts; financial matters with William Elliott and others; news of trouble between Indians and U. S. troops, with three companies from his county and a company of volunteers, minute men ("Silver Greys") consisting of 100 men under Captain James Brannon; frost damage to corn and cotton crops. 1838 May 30
  - D. W. Counts, Public Treasurer, Treasury Department, Newbern, North Carolina to J[ohn G. S[tanley], Clerk of the County Court of Craven, Newbern, North Carolina: land assessment in Craven County, North Carolina. 1838 Sep/Oct 9
  - H. Hubbard, LaGrange, [Illinois], to R. M. Hubbard, Niagara Company, Lockport, New York: wheat harvest; Canaal Bank closing; land grants and settlements; description and prospects for the LaGrange area; prices of wheat, corn, oats, and potatoes in Milwaukee,[Wisconsin], as well as the price of cattle and hogs. 1840 Jul 23
  - M. A. Marshall and E. W. Marshall, Gaston, Alabama, to Andrew McCants, Daviston, Talbot County, Georgia: cotton harvest, corn crops in area; slave trade; contested elections. 1841 May 26
  - Elijah [ ], Yazoo County, Mississippi, to Andrew McCants, Union Post Office, Georgia: contagious diseases, such as yellow fever, in area; description of travels through Mississippi, western Tennessee, Arkansas, and Louisiana; lively discussion of the city of New Orleans and its inhabitants and their activities. 1841 Nov 1
  - J. L. Winfield, Brownsville, Tennessee, to Mayor Robert Hairston, Columbus, Mississippi: advice on land in Tennessee owned by Hairston. 1842 Apr 22
  - William Hill, Raleigh, North Carolina, to James G. Stanley, Newbern, North Carolina: sending a copy of the record of the grant to John Hill. 1849 Apr 23
  - O. E. Pike, Montevallo, Alabama: re G. W. Johnson, of Farmington, North Carolina, leaving Shelby County, Alabama. 1849 Jul 11
- Series V: North Carolina Counties General, 1851-1878
  - John B. Doggett, Monticello, Jefferson County, [ ], to John Tillory, Halifax Town, Halifax County, North Carolina: request to his brother to come west and accompany him back east because of ill health. 1851 Mar 14
  - N. S. W., to "Nellie": personal and friendly. 1854 Jan 7
  - Sicilie T. House, to her cousin: quilting; personal and family news. 1854 Jan 12
  - N. G. Hamilton, Clay County, Georgia, to J. W. McCants: personal news; crops doing well; religious meetings and weddings. 1856 Aug 20
  - H[ilary] G[oode] Richardson, Haymarket, Virginia, to John R. Raine, Wentworth, Rockingham County, North Carolina: in the "midst of a bloody war with Lincoln & his Black Republican horde"; North Carolina being "one of the bright stars of the So. Confederacy"; much on conflict between states. 1861 May 23
  - T. C. Hauser, Gadkin County, North Carolina: declaration of ownership of one male slave between ages of 15 and 50 named "Dan," and another hired temporarily between ages of 35 and 40; and the fact that "Dan" has rheumatism. 1863 Oct
  - [ ], Bladen County, North Carolina, to Kate McGeachy: personal and family news of adolescent. 1864 Jul 29
  - [Addie?], to J. J. McCants: personal and family news; thoughts on General [Robert E.] Lee never giving up Richmond. 1865 Mar 9
  - H[enry] P[arker] Sartwell, Penn Yan, New York, to Dr. Easley: impending botany publications by [Asa] Gray (1810-1888) and others. 1865 Jun 28
  - Jimmy J. Whittle, Cusseta, Georgia, to J. J. "Jack" McCants: personal news written to an old friend and school mate; dating women. 1867 Feb 12
  - Jimmy J. Whittle, Cusseta, Georgia, to J. J. "Jack" McCants: personal; thoughts on marriage. 1867 May 10
  - F. D. C., Castleton, Vermont, to Camilla A. Clingman: life of a medical student at school in Castleton, Vermont. 1878 May 10
  - R. H. Dudley to N. K. Trout, Staunton, Virginia: financial matters. n.d.